Guide to the Allen R. Maxwell Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Research, 1875-circa 2010; Series II
  - Brunei
    - General
      - "The Category of Malay and Brunei", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Outline: "Social Groups and Ethnic Classification in Northwest Borneo", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - "Malay Polysemy and Political Power", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Gazateer of Brunei settlements, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - "A Brunei Letter to Manila", 1975 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - "Introduction to Borneo", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - "A New Bibliography of Brunei Darussalam" (review article), Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - "The Concept of Social Class in the Analysis of Brunei Social Structure", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - "The Origin of the Name Sabah and Brunei Directional Orientation", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Commemorative medal for the coronation of the Sultan, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - "Getting into Field Research in Brunei: An Autobiographical Sketch", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - "The Cultural Construction of Danger in Brunei", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - The Kadayan as ethnically distinct with notes, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - "Introduction to the Kadayan", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - Brunei created awards, 1955-1968 (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - Kadayan death, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Social structure of Brunei, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Research notes on ethnic classification, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Sarawak
    - Ethnohistory
      - 1986 Balui Diary (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - "Balui Reconnaissances: The Badang Kenyah of Long Gang", Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 23, Folder 2-3)
      - A survey of the oral traditions of Sarawak, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Recording oral traditions and language, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - "Government Polices and Ethnic Tension: the Historical Sources of Orang Ulu-Iban Conflict in Sarwak", Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Exchanges with Carol Rubenstein on Orang Ulu oral traditions, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Research notes, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Sarawak research notes and Jawi transliteration, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Cetera Shayk Uthman
      - Preliminary romanization of the Cetera Shaykh Uthman with notes. Version 2, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Second romanization and annotations of the Cetera Shaykh Uthman, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Second romanization with annotations and notes of the Cetra Shaykh Uthman, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Preliminary romanization of the Cetra Shaykh Uthman with notes, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Preliminary romanization of the Cetra Shaykh Uthman, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Manuscript draft of the Cetera Syekh Othman, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Cetera Syekh Othman research notes, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Fieldbooks
      - Sarawak word lists, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Sarawak fieldbooks, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 2-4)
      - Sarawak ethnic group notes fieldbook, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Sarawak epic research notes, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Shaikh Usman notes, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Sarawak Kadazan language research notes, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Sarawak geneologies, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - General
      - "Serita Tugau Raja Melanau", 1971 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Notes on kapuhunan from dictionaries, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Sarawak Swedesh lists, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Iban research notes, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Sarawak export data, 1875-1986 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Sarawak assorted research notes, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - Assorted Brunei/Sarawak maps, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Bangar-Belaban map, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Batu-Apoi map, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Assorted data analysis, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Royal genealogies, Sarawak, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 27, Folder 5-6)
      - Fieldwork sketches/illustrations, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - Royal genealogies, Sarawak, Circa 1985-circa 2010 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - General Anthropological writings
    - Kinship
      - The development of human society and the loss of innocence, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - "Genealogy, Ancestry, and the World's Population", Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - "Morgan's Classificatory Systems of Relationship and Types of Kinship Terminology", 1984 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Universal theories of kintypes, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Crow and Omaha kinship rules, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Notes on promiscuous intercourse, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Kalmuk reciprocal sets and write-up, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - "Provisional Documentation ANTHROPAC 2.6", 1988-1989 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Language and Linguistics
      - Lexicostatistical classification, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Burmese language, ethnicity, and culture cards, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Critical notes on Naven, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - National Science Foundation Institute software availability list, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - Hesperon linkage, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Linguistic notes, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - A checklist of anthropological field supplies, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Grant applications
    - Department of State Scholar Diplomat series, 1977-1978 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Fulbright applications, 1984-1993 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Fulbright related Malaysia government documents, 1985-2005 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Additional grants, 1979-1992 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - University of Alabama Research Grants Committee, 1981-1989 (Box 29, Folder 12)
- Teaching, 1945-circa 2010; Series III
  This series includes materials related to Maxwell's career and teaching at Barnard College and the University of Alabama. It includes syllabi and lecture notes, promotion and professional activity portfolios, materials related to the "Sources of Heroin" conference at the University of Alabama, and related documents pertaining to his professional academic life.
  - Barnard College ethnic relations course, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Linguistics syllabi, 1974-1993 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Linguistics lecture notes, 1969-1993 (Box 30, Folder 3-4)
  - Social anthropology syllabi, 1964-2008 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Social anthropology lecture notes, 1991-1995 (Box 30, Folder 6-9)
  - Promotion and professional activity portfolios
    - Curriculum Vitae, 1984 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Evidence of teaching quality, 1977-1984 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Other instructional activities, 1984 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Administrative responsibilities, 1975-1983 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Publications, 1966-1984 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Varia, 1967-1984 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Evidence of quality of research, 1970-1984 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Manuscripts accepted for publication, 1983-1984 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Manuscripts submitted for publication, 1980-1984 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Manuscripts in preparation, 1978-1984 (Box 31, Folder 10-11)
    - Papers presented, 1973-1984 (Box 32, Folder 1-3)
    - Dissertation, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Sabbatical leave fall 1982 report (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Sabbatical leave report, 2001 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Grant applications, 1967-1984 (Box 33, Folder 3-4)
    - External service contributions, 1969-1984 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Committee assignments, 1974-1984 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Other professional service activities, 1977-1984 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Honors and awards, 1977-1980 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Sources of Heroin conference
    - Sources of Heroin conference correspondence, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 4-5)
    - Sources of Heroin conference, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - General
    - Curriculum Vitae, 2002 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Reunion books and diplomas, 1945-1987 (Box 34, Folder 8-9)
    - Certificates, 1963-1997 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Jane Maxwell, 1985-1986 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Address books and business cards, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Indonesian and Malay learning materials, 1950-1960 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Proposed plan of study in Celebes, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - North Borneo ephemera, 1966-1969 (Box 35, Folder 5)
- Visual materials, Circa 1913-circa 2010; Series IV
  This series consists of color photographic slides, photographs, posters, maps, and kinship diagrams. Photographs include images of the Brunei royal family created and collected by Maxwell in the field. The geographical foci of these materials are Brunei, Sarawak, Malaya, and Java.
  - Postcards and photographs
    - Sarawak postcards, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 36, Folder 1-5)
    - Sarawak postcards and photographs, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Brunei postcards, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Stella inscription photographs from Brunei, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 36, Folder 8-9)
    - Large stella inscription photographs and maps from Brunei, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Large assorted Borneo photographs, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Japanese occupation photographs, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Allen Maxwell learning traditional dance photographs, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - General photos, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Color slides
    - Artifacts: cemetaries, 1968-1970 (Box 37)
    - Artifacts: graffiti, 1968-1989 (Box 37)
    - Built landscapes, 1968-1989 (Box 37)
    - Built landscapes, 1968-1989 (Box 38)
    - Environment, 1968-1986 (Box 39)
    - Environment, 1968-1986 (Box 40)
    - People, 1968-1986 (Box 41)
    - People, 1968-1986 (Box 42)
    - People, 1986-1986 (Box 43)
    - People, 1986-1986 (Box 44)
  - Posters, maps, kinship diagrams, and land deeds
    - Maps of Malaya, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 45)
    - Java native food crops, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 45)
    - Sarawak Brunei and Sabah with location notes by Maxwell in red pencil, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 45)
    - Sarawak color coded by state or district, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 45)
    - Kuching Town in color, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 45)
    - Hydroelectric projects Sarawak, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 45)
    - Road development Sarawak, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 45)
    - British Borneo, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 45)
    - Dunia Islam, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 45)
    - Salasilah in Jawi, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 45)
    - Brunei hand drawn transparency, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 45)
    - North Borneo hand drawn transparency, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 45)
    - North Borneo hand drawn maps, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 45)
    - Salasilah, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 46)
    - Brunei royal title rankings, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 46)
    - A photograph of the Sultan of Brunei, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 46)
    - Brunei salasilah, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 46)
    - Charles Brook Land Transfers, 1913-1937 (Box 46)
    - Mortgage deeds memoranda of charge, 1957-1960 (Box 46)
    - Lexical comparison chart for Borneo Malay dialects, Circa 1968-circa 2010 (Box 46)
- Audio recordings, 1968-circa 1989; Series V
  This series contains field recordings of elicited and naturally-discourse, music performances, and oral histories collected in North Borneo. Some of these recordings feature Maxwell interacting with Kadayan interlocutors, eliciting vocabulary and data related to kinship structure within Kadayan society. Other recordings by Maxwell are related to research on traditional music forms in North Borneo.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - Liman stories - X1-ILA3, 1970; 1 (Box 47)
  - Liman stories - X2-ILB3, 1970; 1 (Box 48)
  - Hj. Pandin place names - X3-IRC1, 1970; 1 (Box 49)
  - Jumat - X4a-IRD1, 1970; 1 (Box 50)
  - Jumat X4b-IRC2, 1970; 1 (Box 51)
  - Malay prose, 1968-1971; 1 (Box 52)
  - Malay prose - male speaker, 1968-1971; 1 (Box 53)
  - Malay conversation with Maxwell, 1968-1971; 1 (Box 54)
  - Consultation between Maxwell and Kadayan informants, 1968-1971; 1 (Box 55)
  - Consultation between Maxwell and Kadayan informants, 1968-1971; 1 (Box 56)
  - Kadayan folk songs with trading pantun verses. Female voice., Circa 1968-circa 1971; 1 (Box 76)
  - Kadayan male vocal music, Circa 1968-circa 1971; 1 (Box 77)
  - Female vocalist with kendhang accompaniment, Circa 1968-circa 1971; 1 (Box 78)
  - Music featuring male vocals and gambus and frame drum accompaniment, Circa 1968-circa 1971; 1 (Box 80)
  - Vocal music with accompaniment, including frame drum, Circa 1968-circa 1971; 1 (Box 79)
  - Female and male vocalists trading verses with two frame drums accompanying, Circa 1968-circa 1971; 1 (Box 81)
  - Music and male vocals, Circa 1968-circa 1971; 1 (Box 82)
  - Male and female individual vocals with frame drum and gambus, Circa 1968-circa 1971; 1 (Box 83)
  - Male and female vocals and music, Circa 1968-circa 1971; 1 (Box 84)
  - Music and male vocals with frame drum and gambus accompaniment, Circa 1968-circa 1971; 1 (Box 85)
  - Instrumentals- gambus accompaniment on side one, vocals and instrumentals on side two, Circa 1968-circa 1971; 1 (Box 86)
  - Solo stringed instrument with voice over at beginnings in Malay (Side B blank), Circa 1975-circa 1988; 1 (Box 87)
  - Commercially produced Malaysian and western pop music with female vocals on side A and male vocals on side B, Circa 1980-circa 1989; 1 (Box 88)
  - Commercially produced Malaysian pop music, Circa 1980-circa 1989; 1 (Box 89)
  - Field recording of "Badang" folk tale, Circa 1975-circa 1988; 1 (Box 90)
  - Field recording of "Badang" folk tale, Circa 1975-circa 1988; 1 (Box 91)
  - Recording of "Program Sakan Nua" radio program and sung recitations by a solo male and a solo female vocalists., Circa 1975-circa 1988; 1 (Box 92)
  - Field recording of a male speaker from the Sihan tribe, side B blank, Circa 1975-circa 1988; 1 (Box 93)
- Malay lexicon and field notecards, 1968-1988; Series VI
  The series consists of 3x5 and 4x6 index cards. Maxwell used the cards to record data related to his linguistic and ethnographic fieldwork, a mode of data collection promulgated by his dissertation supervisor, Harold C. Conklin. The aim of creating the cards was to create a working database centered on topics of Kadayan and Malay language and writing traditions, and kinship structure and social relations.
  - Brunei Malay and Kadayan lexicon and field notecards
    - A-BA (3x5), 1968-1971 (Box 57)
    - BA (continued)-BU (3x5), 1968-1971 (Box 58)
    - BU (continued)-GA (3x5), 1968-1971 (Box 59)
    - GA (continued)-I (3x5), 1968-1971 (Box 60)
    - J-KA (3x5), 1968-1971 (Box 61)
    - KA (continued)-LA (3x5), 1968-1971 (Box 62)
    - LA (continued)-MA (3x5), 1968-1971 (Box 63)
    - MA (continued)-PA (3x5), 1968-1971 (Box 64)
    - PA (continued)-PO (3x5), 1968-1971 (Box 65)
    - PR-SA (3x5), 1968-1971 (Box 66)
    - SA-SY (3x5), 1968-1971 (Box 67)
    - T-TE (3x5), 1968-1971 (Box 68)
    - TH-Z (3x5), 1968-1971 (Box 69)
    - Lexicon key cards (3x5), 1968-1971 (Box 69)
    - Anthropological theory cards (3x5), 1968-1986 (Box 69)
    - Adat Istiadat diraja (3x5), 1968-1986 (Box 70)
  - Brunei and Sarawak Malay lexicon and field notecards
    - Comparative notes on Borneo language, culture, and environment (4x6), 1968-1971 (Box 71)
    - Language, culture, and environment in Brunei (4x6), 1968-1971 (Box 72)
    - Language, culture, and environment in Brunei (continued) (4x6), 1968-1971 (Box 73)
    - Kadayan and Malay phonology (4x6), 1968-1971 (Box 73)
    - Ethnicity notes (4x6), 1968-1971 (Box 73)
    - Malay lexicon (4x6), 1968-1971 (Box 73)
    - Malay names (4x6), 1968-1971 (Box 73)
    - Death and dying in Brunei (4x6), 1968-1971 (Box 73)
    - Field notes (4x6), 1968-1971 (Box 73)
    - Annotated Brunei bibliography (4x6), 1968-1971 (Box 73)
    - Sarawak oral histories (4x6), 1985-1986 (Box 74)
    - Cetera Syaikh Uthman (4x6), 1985 (Box 75)
    - Belaga Malay community (4x6), 1988 (Box 75)
- Computer disks, Circa 1968-circa 2010; Series VII (Box 94–96)
  This is a format-driven series containing lexico-statistical analyses of his life's major work: the Syair Awang Simawn, a classical epic focused on the founding of Brunei. Other files within this category include a collection of his unpublished papers, and software used to analyze linguistic data relating to the kinship structures of Brunei and Sarawak's people.
  Closed until processed.
  - Syair Awang Simawn
  - Kinship
  - Belaga and Lowe diaries
  - Bukan Balum and Kilat data
  - General anthropology papers